<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>The Toolshed</title>
        <link>https://wolfadex.github.io/blog/posts</link>
        <description>Musings on web development tools</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 14:59:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
        <generator>Elmstatic</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <image>
            <title>The Toolshed</title>
            <url>https://wolfadex.github.io/blog/img/logo.png</url>
            <link>https://wolfadex.github.io/blog/posts</link>
        </image>
        <copyright>Copyright: T. Wolfgang Schuster</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[20 Years of Web]]></title>
            <link>https://wolfadex.github.io/blog/posts/2020-03-25-20-years-of-web</link>
            <guid>https://wolfadex.github.io/blog/posts/2020-03-25-20-years-of-web</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
It occurred to me last night that I've been building websites, either professionally or as a hobby, for over 20 years now! I built my first website in a computer class in the 6th grade using nothing more than a text editor and trial & error. Things have come a long ways since then.

In college I learned Macromedia Dreamweaver and Macromedia Flash. My first software job was all about Sublime Text 2 and ExtJS. Now when I mention most of those things I get looks of confusion.

Everyone seems to be...]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Frameworks Comparison - Part 1 - Imba]]></title>
            <link>https://wolfadex.github.io/blog/posts/2020-03-29-frameworks-part-1-imba</link>
            <guid>https://wolfadex.github.io/blog/posts/2020-03-29-frameworks-part-1-imba</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
I decided to go ahead and test out various front end frameworks. I wanted to see what I can learn from them, what I enjoy, and what I find difficult. For each I'll be building a basic Todo app that stores values in localStorage, and a Quiz app that stores scores in localStorage. If you'd like to see the code, it'll be available ay github.com/wolfadex/framework-comparison.

The Todo app is just for learning the framework and getting used to it. The Quiz app will be for something a little more in...]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Frameworks Comparison - Part 2 - Nim + Karax]]></title>
            <link>https://wolfadex.github.io/blog/posts/2020-03-31-frameworks-part-2-nim-karax</link>
            <guid>https://wolfadex.github.io/blog/posts/2020-03-31-frameworks-part-2-nim-karax</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
Next up in frameworks is Karax which is written in Nim. A small snippet of what Karax for those who are interested:

include karax / prelude

var lines: seq[kstring] = @[]

proc createDom(): VNode =
  result = buildHtml(tdiv):
    button:
      text "Say hello!"
      proc onclick(ev: Event; n: VNode) =
        lines.add "Hello simulated universe"
    for x in lines:
      tdiv:
        text x

setRenderer createDom

Now I've written some Nim before. I did the first couple Advent of Code 2020 i...]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Framework Agnostic Localization]]></title>
            <link>https://wolfadex.github.io/blog/posts/2020-04-20-framework-agnostic-localization</link>
            <guid>https://wolfadex.github.io/blog/posts/2020-04-20-framework-agnostic-localization</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
Across my various web projects, adding localization has always required learning how to use my current framework's popular localization library. It was always frustrating having to learn a new library to get the same localization files on the screen. I assumed I was the only one having this problem so I went about my work accepting it as fact. Recently though I began hearing of others having the same struggle, and it finally came to me. Web components!

At the same time I was also reading about...]]></description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
